Okay, so I have this docs directory and
I have a file called plan.mmd
and here it is highlevel steps for the
project. I have got 10 parts of building
this that I've written out. Now we
didn't need to do it this way. We could
have the LLM just write the 10 steps
itself and that's very much a decision
about whether you want to first have it
do a highle plan which is super common
in these things. But I am quite
opinionated on this and I wanted to set
I wanted to put it on guard rails and I
recommend you do too. If you have
opinions on this, let me take you
through this plan and you'll see what I
mean about how how simply I want to take
it. Part one is itself plan enrich this
document to plan out each of these parts
in detail with substeps listed out as a
checklist to be checked off by the agent
and with tests and success criteria for
each. Also create an agents.mmd file
inside the front-end directory. There's
nothing there that describes the
existing code there. Ensure the user
checks and approves the plan. That seems
like a really robust first step. Second
step, scaffolding. Set up the docker
infrastructure, the back end with fast
API and write the start and stop scripts
in the scripts directory. This should
serve example static HTML to confirm a
hello world example running locally and
also making an API call. It's good
stuff. As I say, an LLM will write this
for you if you don't want to do this. If
you're a senior engineer, then hopefully
you know where I'm coming from. This is
a very good methodical way to build
slowly. The thing I have in my mind
always is that if any one of these steps
doesn't work, then I have a really good
sense of how to dig in and figure out
why with with the co-pilot. And I always
try and work that way. Each step should
be something that that I know how to dig
into that. Part three, add in the front
end now update. So the front end is
built and served so the demo cam board
is on display. Part four, the fake user
signin experience. Part five, database
model. Set up the database schema.
Document the approach and get user sign
off. Part six, backend. Add API roots so
the backend can read and change the
canban. Test it thoroughly. The database
should be created if it doesn't exist.
And then of course part seven bring the
front end and the back end together. Now
by part seven we'll be able to use the
front end to actually call the back end.
We'll be able to move around uh cards on
on the canban board and the database
will update. We should be able to log
out and log in again and see it there.
See it remaining and that will be cool.
Part eight is is the AI connectivity
allow the backends to make an AI call
via open router test it with two plus
two. Part nine is so that that that
simple plumbing is extended so that we
could send the cambban board send a
question and get back an answer and
potentially a change to the camban. And
finally, part 10 is adding a beautiful
widget supporting full AI chat and
allowing the LLM to change the camban
board. That's the plan. Okay. So, this
is just the kind of preparation that one
does to get things off on the right
footing. Everything is is tight. We know
what we want to do. You don't need to
lay out the 10 highle steps like this,
but if you know what you what you want,
then you should. Uh but you could also
have it come up with a highle plan. All
right. And with all of this, it's time
now I'm going to make this look nice and
neat. Um, everything is is of course at
this point checked in and on GitHub. So
we we we have a snapshot of the code as
it is. And one of the crucial points I'm
going to be making to you is that when
you work in this way, you go step by
step. You're always checkpointing by
doing by taking like a like a git commit
at each point. So you can always walk
back if you need to. That's always that
option is always available to you and
indeed you should take it if you're not
happy with where you get to. It's time
for us to do part one. Okay, I'm going
to make the agent nice and big over
here. I'm going to make sure I'm going
to go with the GPT52 codeex. We've had a
good run with this. It made the canvan
front end. We should let it keep going.
Okay. And now I'm going to say um please
review agents.mmd
and the plan and proceed with and let me
know if you have any questions. That's
the first way to start. And let me know
if you have any questions.
Do not do any work yet.
That's always a great way to start. Ask
ask me to uh enable GPT 5.2. Ask me
questions is a great way to start.
That's a a really good way of doing it.
We've got lots of screens here. Okay, so
it's got some questions. Number one, do
you want me to enrich Plan.md with
detailed checklist, tests, and success
criteria? Uh number two, should I create
the front-end agents as part of the plan
enrichment or only after plan
improvement? Number three, for
comprehensive tests, you have a minimum
coverage target or specific test types
you want prioritized. These all seem
like they're they're kind of um uh easy
easy questions. It hasn't found anything
particularly uh particularly
complicated. So I think uh number one is
is is yes uh create uh yes enrich plan
MD.
Uh two yes create agents.m MD for front
end right away.
three. Uh so do we have a minimum uh uh
coverage target um uh 80%
uh unit test coverage
minimum
and robust uh integration testing.
Go ahead
with part one. All right. Off it goes.
Off it goes. Okay. So, it's now going to
go off and do this. And of course, as
you can see, we're I'm just taking it
step by step. I'm not in YOLO mode. And
so, I'm I'm here expecting to approve
things and check things as they come.
And I'm only going to ever give it
permission to do one more step because
we're doing it the proper way. We're
doing it the slow, methodical way, which
is the way to build bulletproof systems
with an AI co-pilot like Copilot. I will
see you in a minute. Okay, it didn't
take long at all and it's uh it's
updated the project plan. Let me make
this screen a bit better size for us.
Here is the detailed project plan. Um
and you can see it has indeed for for
part one. It's it's put check boxes by
everything. Um and uh plan is detailed
and actionable. Let's have a look. We'll
be the judge of that. Uh so it's got a
docker file. That's what I like to see.
Creating this adding minimal read me
notes. It knows that I want it to be
minimal. Uh, ensure UV is used inside
the container. That's correct. Good. Set
up scripts. Okay. I like the fact that
it's got some tests here. It's got a
health endpoint. That's a that's a nice
nice plan indeed. It's got success
criteria listed out here. I like that.
Uh, checklist here. Um, and then um
front end. This seems good. Yes. Yes.
Fake user signin experience. Yes.
Database modeling. Okay. Um, create SQL
light database implement CRUD endpoints.
That's good. This all looks perfectly
reasonable. You should be doing this,
too. We're looking for any signs of
anything that we don't like, but it all
looks good to me. A simple endpoint.
Yes. Integration test that that
validates the two plus two. Um, okay.
Yep. That seems that seems fine. And
build sidebar. Um, okay. This seems um
this seems very good to me. I think all
10 parts are understood. Um now we also
want to look at the agents.mmd that it
should have created here. Uh and let's
see. Okay, good. It is indeed app router
if you know about that. This all seems
great. Uh it's pretty short, but that's
fine. Uh okay, good, good, good, good,
good. All right, I'm pretty happy with
that. Uh so we're going to say yes to
approve this and move on to step two.
All right. So, confirmed, approved,
approved. Onto step two.
All right. Which is, of course, this
scaffolding. So, we'll now let it do
this. And you should be doing the same.
And I realize it feels like it it feels
like we're going in such small steps
after we've yoloed yesterday. You're
thinking, "Oh, why can't I just tell it
do all 10 steps? Just do all 10 steps.
I'll come back later." But the thing is,
this is too big a deal. If we do all 10
steps, it will go off the rails and
things will go wrong. You could always
try if you want if you want to be bold,
you want to be brave because you can
always go back and get to where we were.
So, for sure, you could just say, "Hey,
let's do all 10 steps." Uh, but I think
you'll find as as you and I will
experience. I'm sure we're going to hit
some roadblocks along the way. And if we
just let it do all of its thing, things
would go ary. All right, I'll see you in
a second when we have our part two done.
Okay, so it says part two scaffolding is
in place. Uh, it's got a fast API back
end. It's got all of this. Um, now what
I'm interested in is whether it has
actually tested it itself. I think it's
just inspected. So, that's no good. Did
Did you test part two yourself?
Let's see. No, I did not run test yet.
Please run tests thoroughly.
Bring up the server.
Make sure it works.
Check the um the the uh the the roots.
Bring it down.
Let me know
when you are confident.
Okay, that's a great example. You see,
it just wanted to move on. It just said
two is done and and it hadn't actually
tested it. Uh the uh create a virtual
environment
uh allow.
Why is it doing this exactly? This seems
a bit strange. We're meant to be using
UV. We're not expecting a
requirements.ext.
Let's see what's happening here. I'm
suspicious. I am suspicious. I see a
requirements.ext.
Okay, we'll let it do its thing.
Um,
and uh, yeah, we'll see where this goes
in the in the end. I will see you back
here in a second. So, it's been running
various commands and I've been pressing
allow, looking at them, understanding
what it's doing. It's been stuck with
some test failures and trying things
again. And now I know what these things
are doing. So, I know that they're safe
and I've been allowing them. If you know
it already, if you if you're someone
that's that's worked with this before,
you can allow it. If you don't know,
then you can get a sense for it. You can
you can ask chat GPT uh to to explain
what's going on. Get get a second pair
of eyes or you can deny and then and
then just ask it to explain what it's
doing and why. But this is it's it's for
someone if if you're new to this area,
then not only is this important for you
to make sure that you're satisfied with
everything that's happening, but as I
say, it's also this amazing learning
opportunity to to to inquire and see
what it takes to build this kind of
software.